Contact

djchadwick@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ danieljchadwick (LinkedIn) danielchadwick.co.uk (Blog)

Top Skills

PHP

SQL

LESS (Stylesheet Language)

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

98-368: MTA: Mobility and Device

Fundamentals

98-367: MTA: Security

Fundamentals

98-365: MTA: Windows® Server Administration Fundamentals

98-349: MTA: Windows® Operating

System Fundamentals

98-375: MTA: HTML5 Application Development Fundamentals

Daniel Chadwick

Developer at Wren Kitchens

Kingston upon Hull, England Metropolitan Area

Summary

Developer at Wren Kitchens working with mainly PHP7/Symfony, LESS/CSS, JavaScript, Twig/HTML, MySQL on a variety of internal and external services.

I studied at the University of Hull for my BSc Computer Science. Whilst at University I mainly used C# but have developed in PHP, Java, C++, C and JavaScript and studied an array of key concepts such as MVC frameworks, data structures, and algorithms to name a few.

Prior to studying I worked for 2 years at an online eCommerce retailer as a Full Stack Developer focusing on PHP eCommerce/management systems, scripts and software environments.

Experience

Wren Kitchens

1 year 7 months

Developer

August 2020 - Present (5 months)

Barton upon Humber, England, United Kingdom

Junior Developer

June 2019 - August 2020 (1 year 3 months)

Barton-upon-Humber, North Lincolnshire, United Kingdom

Working on a variety of services, internal and external, with:

- PHP 7
- Symfony 3/4
- SQL (MySQL 8)
- JavaScript
- Twig
- LESS/CSS
- Testing (PHPUnit/Behat)
- RabbitMQ

- AWS (S3, Cloudwatch)
- RESTful APIs
- Docker
- Elasticsearch

Workwear Outlet
Full Stack Developer
May 2017 - September 2018 (1 year 5 months)
Blackburn, United Kingdom

Technology:

PHP 5.6, MySQL 5, HTML/CSS/JS hosted on onsite managed VMware server running CentOS6/7 VMs.

Also worked with Opencart, Magento, osCommerce sales platforms with a COTS stock management system.

Worked with the 3rd party courier services such as Yodel and DPD for domestic and international order fulfilment.

Managed the technology stacks for all the brands under and including the Workwear Outlet family such as SnickersDirect, SafetyBootsUK, PowertoolDirect.

Role also included:

UI/UX, content management, internal systems development including order processing, logistics, email marketing and business reporting.

Workwear Outlet

IT Apprentice

January 2015 - September 2016 (1 year 9 months)

Training completed with mentorship within the company for development and operations alongside training blocks with QA Apprenticeships. I passed all my Microsoft Technology Associate certifications with flying colours and, at the time, was working towards a Cisco Certified Network Associate certification.

Transitioned to development early on working with:

- PHP 5.6,
- MySQL 5,
- HTML/CSS/JS hosted on onsite managed VMware server running CentOS6/7 VMs.

Also worked with Opencart, Magento, osCommerce sales platforms with a COTS stock management system.

Worked with the 3rd party courier services such as Yodel and DPD for domestic and international order fulfilment.

Managed the technology stacks for all the brands under and including the Workwear Outlet family such as SnickersDirect, SafetyBootsUK, PowertoolDirect.

Role also included:

UI/UX, content management, internal systems development including order processing, logistics, email marketing and business reporting.

Between 2016-2018 I worked part time whilst studying at the University of Hull.

Education

The University of Hull Bachelor's Degree (Hons), Computer Science · (2016 - 2019)

QA Apprenticeships

Apprenticeship training, Level 3 ICT Systems and Principles / ICT Professional Competence · (2015 - 2016)

Ribblesdale High School 9 GCSEs A* - B · (2009 - 2014)